KARTHIKEYAN R

Software Developer

Email Id : amkarthikeyan15@gmail.com

LinkedIn : amkarthikeyan-r

GitHub : Karthikeyan-Ramesh

Phone Number: +91 882 546 1535

Portfolio : karthikeyan/portfolio

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced and skilled software development professional with 4 years of experience in Full Stack development using struts and Spring Boot web technologies in Java. My career objective is to be an outstanding person in the field I work in. I want to pursue a highly challenging and creative career where I can apply my existing knowledge and creativity as well as acquire new skills and contribute effectively to the organization and its growth.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java.

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, JSON, JavaScript, Struts, Hibernate, Morphia, Spring Boot, Angular, Spring Cloud, JSP.

Message Queue: Apache Kafka, JMS. Databases: MySQL, MongoDB.

Tools: Git, GitHub, Microservices, Elastic Search, GCD, Junit, Tomcat, GoCD, Docker, Shopify, BigCommerce

EDUCATION

Vel Tech Multitech DR. RR & DR. SR Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science (CGPA:7.2).

Chennai, India 2015 - 2019

2013 2017

Chennai, India, August 2021 - Present

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Radial Omnichannel Technologies India Pvt Ltd

Software Analyst - (FulFillment & Supply Chain Technology)

- Devised an algorithm, which processes an automation strategy to manage the pick, pack, and ship of our orders.
- Developed a client connector as a child service from scratch in an E-commerce connector as per client requirements.
- Designed a scheduler to Back traverse the orders based on execution stages and also added one of our clients to our ROM family.
- Developed a service from scratch using the Spring Cloud approach, which implements schedulers, listeners, and SFTP file handlers.
- Implemented WebSocket in our system to manage the shipment calls by connecting with our client system for tracking orders.

Inswit Software Pvt Ltd

Chennai, India, June 2020 - August 2021

Software Developer

- Migrated our Monolithic codebase into three Microservices for horizontal scalability as well as migrated one of our CHATBOT jersey REST APIs to Spring Boot REST API and added Spring Boot Security.
- Created the Audit Trail Microservice from scratch by leveraging the CORS policy, Apache Kafka, and Spring Boot Security and stored the trail details in MongoDB, and also implemented Junit Testcases for our REST API's in each Microservices.
- Designed the Audit component in Angular which stores trail details and provided a download option for our clients through the REST API using Java and also designed the Web forms for our clients in React.
- Finally made the setup of Microservices with the help of Git version control and make it a war file and deployed it on our local machine for BDD purposes.

IDB Technologies Pvt Ltd

Chennai, India, January 2019 – February 2020

Junior java developer

- Devised an algorithm, to keep track of our client's employee's productivity by using ERP technology and generated a sheet to show the reports of their client's activities.
- I have maintained the CONBUILD project from scratch by using JAVA, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Hibernate, Bootstrap, MySQL, JSP, and struts frameworks and also designed invoices for our clients using JSP.
- Implemented CRM technology to provide chat service in issue tracking applications to interact more effectively using PHP.
- Used the GitHub repository to the made setup up our project and deploy it on our company's local server for BDD purposes.